당신은 이 gate에 입력값을
0으로 곱한 것을 쓸 수 있습니다.
You can also write at those gates as
multiplying the inputs either by 0,
그때는 그 gate가 닫힌것이 됩니다.
또는 1을 곱하면, 그 gate는 열리것이 됩니다.
when the gate is closed, or
by 1, when the gate is open.
모두 좋습니다. 그러나,neural networks과
같이 이해해야 할 것은 무엇인가요?
That's all fine, but what does it
have to do with neural networks?
각각의 gate에서 가부에 대한 결정을 하는 대신에
Imagine that instead of having
binary decisions at each gate,
당신은 연속적인 결정을 하는것에 대해서 상상해보자.
you had continuous decisions.
예를 들어, 입력에 yes-no gate 대신에
입력값을 가지고 오고
For example, instead of yes-no gate
at the input, you take the input and
0과 1사이의 어떤 값으로 곱할 수 있습니다.
multiply it by a value
that's between 0 and 1.
만약 정확히 0 이라면, 입력값은 들어올 수 없습니다.
If it's exactly 0, no input comes in.
만약 정확히 1이라면, 입력값
전체를 메모리에 쓰게 됩니다.
If it's exactly 1,
you write it entirely to memory.
0~1사이의 어떤값은 부분적으로 메모리에 추가하게 됩니다.
Anything in between can be
added partially to the memory.
우리에게 매우 흥미롭게 되었습니다.
Now that becomes very interesting for
만약 곱셈 계수가 연속함수이고,
us, because if that multiplicative
factor is a continuous function
미분가능하다면, 도함수를 가질 수 있다는 의미입니다.
that's also differentiable, that
means we can take derivatives of it.
그리고, 도함수를 통해서 back propagate을
할 수 있다는 의미입니다.
And that also means we can
back propagate through it.
정확히 LSTM이란 것은
That's exactly what an LSTM is.
메모리의 단순한 모델을 가지고 있다는 것입니다.
We take this simple model of memory,
우리는 연속함수를 가지고 모든 것을 대체합니다.
we replace everything with
continuous functions.
RNN의 핵심적인 새로운 Lowell machine을
만들어보자.
And make that the new Lowell
machine that's at the heart
of a recurrent neural network.